Collins-Levine Family Papers
© 2011 University of Connecticut
Collins-Levine Family Papers
undated, 1921-1980.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Collins, Eli Ives.; Collins, Edward R.; Schreiber, Frances F.
.25 linear feet.
The collection contains correspondence, school papers, memorabilia, photographs and ephemera associated with two generations of the Collins and Levine families who attended the University of Connecticut between 1922 and 1948.
MSS20110024
Biography
Eli Ives Collins (Class of 1925) worked on the student newspaper while attending Connecticut Agricultural College. After leaving college, Collins had a successful career as a newspaper reporter and editor, primarily for the Jersey Journal in Jersey City, N.J.
Edward R. Collins (Class of 1928) and Frances F. Schreiber (Class of 1927) met as students attending the Connecticut Agricultural College and married in 1927.
Donald I. Levine (Class of 1949) and member of Phi Epsilon Pi married Laura Ann Collins (Class of 1949), a member of Kappa Alpha Theta. They were married in Stamford, Connecticut, in 1952. Their daughter, Deborah Ann Levine, entered the University in 1971 and obtained multiple degrees. While at the University, she met Jonathan B. Chaires, who received a Ph.D. in biophysics from the University. They married in 1981.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, school papers, memorabilia, photographs and ephemera associated with two generations of the Collins and Levine families who attended the University of Connecticut between 1922 and 1948. The materials in the collection are useful in providing a perspective of college life and experiences from the student's point of view.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged chronologically by individual.
Series I: Collins-Levine family papers ( undated, 1921-1980 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
Multiple issues of the Connecticut Campus (1921-1928) have been added to the Archives' holdings of the Connecticut Daily Campus.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Collins, Eli Ives.; Collins, Edward R.; Levine, Donald I.; Schrieber, Frances F.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut.; Connecticut Agricultural College.
Family Names:
Collins.; Levine.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.; School Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The materials were saved and collected by the two generations of Collins and Levine family members who had attended the University of Connecticut
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated by Adam Levine in 2011.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Collins-Levine papers, undated, 1921-1980
  - Eli Ives Collins Correspondence, 1922-1923, 1980 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Eli Ives Collins Handbook and memorabilia, 1922-1923, 1950 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Eli Ives Collins school papers, undated, circa 1922 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Edward R. Collins autograph book, circa 1923 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Edward R. Collins correspondence, 1923-1925 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Edward R. Collins memorabilia, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Frances F. Schreiber correspondence, 1926 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Frances F. Schreiber memorabilia, undated (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Frances F. Schreiber photographs, undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Frances F. Schreiber school papers, circa 1924 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Donald I. Levine photographs, circa 1948 (Box 1:, Folder 11)